ERNESTO FLORES MANRIQUE

Location: San Francisco de Dos Ríos, San José

Contact: 7109-1639

E-mail: efabiofm@gmail.com



PROFILE

Full-stack web developer with two and a half years of experience working on web and hybrid applications development for different business areas, both for local and foreign clients. During that time, I've acquired excellent programming practices, knowledge in server configuration for deploying final product and system requirement and project scope management. High english language proficiency, both oral and written.

EXPERIENCE

Ciris Informatic Solutions

Full-Stack Web Developer

September 2015 - To date

Develop and maintain front and back end of web and hybrid applications for local and foreign customers under a Scrum or Kanban methodology, using mostly Angular, Node, MongoDB and Ionic. Configure and maintain Linux servers to deploy to production the applications using continuous integration tools. Analyze software requirements and estimate project duration. Research and implement latest technologies and best programming practices.

Sykes Latin America S. A.

Customer Service Agent

October 2014 - September 2015

Responsible for providing high quality and accurate resolutions to Intel's internal customers in the United States under stipulated policies and procedures, by answering general inquiries via phone or e-mail.

Ingram Micro CR

Electronic Technician

January 2013 - April 2014

Responsible for repairing mobile devices from a wide range of well-known brands coming from T-Mobile in the United States, going from the troubleshooting process to circuit board components replacement.

EDUCATION

Universidad CENFOTEC

Bachelor degree in Software Engineering Period: January 2014 – To date

Universidad Técnica Nacional

Associate's degree in Electronics

Period: January 2011 - December 2012

Courses

Microcomputers Maintenance and Repair

Universidad de San José. August 2004 – April 2005

Privateacher English Program

OBM Corporation. July 2004 - October 2005

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, JAVA, C++, C#, VB.NET.
- Web Technologies: AngularJS, Ionic, Cordova, Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js 2, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Sass, JSON, XML, Yeoman, Lighttpd, HAProxy, GitLab CI, Bower, NPM, Gulp, ASP.NET.
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, SQL Server.
- Testing Tools: Jasmine, Nightwatch, Tape, PhantomJS, Mocha, Chai, JUnit, Selenium, Cucumber.
- Version Control Software: Git, GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket.
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, Android.

LANGUAGES

■ English: Level: C1 BELT Standard February 2015.

■ Spanish: Level: Native.

REFERENCES

Melissa Odio	6023-4415	Citi	Accounting Analyst
Olman Calvo	8858-8236	Sykes	Team Manager
Rodrigo Paris	6049-4177	Ciris	Developer